Guide to the Parliamentary Speeches, Debates, Etc.
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
[Parliamentary speeches, debates, etc. and other miscellaneous manuscripts]
1401-1700
OSBORN FB159
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.19
(1 volume)
Collection of 115 items, bound together in one volume, and written mainly in the hand of John Browne, but with numerous items in other hands. The entries primarily address Parliamentary activities, particularly in the House of Lords, including several extracts from Parliamentary journals; lists of Parliamentary bills; a copy in Browne's hand of King Charles I's speech at dissolving Parliament in 1640; speeches by Charles II; and records of payments to Parliamentary officers. Other items include a satire on the Earl of Pembroke by Michael Oldisworth and several non-Parliamentary accounts and receipts.
Browne, John, approximately 1608-1691
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn fb159. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
Finance, Public -- Great Britain; Legal documents; Marriage settlements -- Great Britain; Formulas, recipes, etc.; Great Britain -- Officials and employees -- Salaries, etc.; Great Britain -- Politics and government -- 1485-1603; Great Britain -- Politics and government -- 1603-1714; Commonplace books; Charles, King of England, I, 1600-1649; Charles, King of England, II, 1630-1685; Browne, John, approximately 1608-1691; Oldisworth, Michael, 1591-1654?; Gonzaga family; Great Britain. Parliament; Great Britain. Parliament. House of Lords; Braye, Alfred Verney-Cave, Baron, 1849-1928 -- Bookplate
- Osborn fb159
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [Memorandum on property, c. 15th century]: (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      2 p.
      Anonymous MS.
      f.1.
  - BOWYER, ROBERT, D. 1621.
    - [Notes on bills and proceedings in Parliament during the late 16th and 17th centuries]: Autograph MS. (Box 1)
      Autograph MS. Draft notes.
      f.2.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691.
    - [Calendar of parliamentary business in the House of Lords, 1641 July 9-Aug 28] (Box 1)
      4 p.
      Autograph MS. Notes of business
      under each day, including committee
      meetings, bills read, etc.
      f.8.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - "Allowances made to Mr Barker, the King's printer", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      [dated 20 Feb 1609/10; 19 Mar
      1609/10; 22 Dec 1610]
      1 p.
      Anonymous MS. Memorandum on payments
      made to Barker for books and paper.
      f.33.
  - SALISBURY, ROBERT CECIL, 1ST EARL, 1563?-1612
    - [Order for a payment to Ralph Ewen, Clerk of Parliament, for special services, 1610 July 28], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      MS copy in the hand of Robert Bowyer.
      Payment authorized by Salisbury and
      Sir Julius Caesar (1558-1636).
      Includes a postscript indicating that
      this payment is not to be taken as a
      precedent, and a note by Bowyer that
      he was ordered to blot out the
      postscript, but left it legible.
      Signed "RB".
      f.34.
  - LOWES, JOHN
    - [Receipts, signed by Lowes and Thomas Wotham, 1611 Nov 22 & 1611/12 Jan 7] (Box 1)
      MS in the hand of Robert Bowyer
      (d.1621). Signed by Lowes of the
      Court of Chancery, and Wotham, Clerk
      of the Rolls, for writs of certiorari
      received from Bowyer, Clerk of
      Parliament.
      f.35.
  - SMITH, SIR THOMAS, D.1609
    - [Note of fees due him as clerk of Parliament, 1601 Oct], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      MS document, signed "Th.Smith".
  - BOWYER, ROBERT, D. 1621.
    - [Contract between between Bowyer, Clerk of Parliament, and Owen Reynolds, deputy clerk, 1609] (Box 1)
      Draft copy with corrections and
      deletions. Agreement on duties and
      fees.
      f.37.
  - COSENS, RALPH
    - [Receipts, signed by Cosens and George Norburie (Norbury), 1610 Nov 8] (Box 1)
      (d.1621). Receipts for writs of
      certiorari received from Bowyer,
      clerk of Parliament.
      f.38.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1610. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - "Fees or rewards for service of the house paid by my [Lordships]", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      [1610/11 Feb 15]
      Anonymous MS. Short list of bishops
      and peers with one or two pounds sums
      assigned to each.
      f.39.
  - BARKER, ROBERT, D.1645
    - [List of books and supplies delivered to the Clerk of Parliament by Barker, the King's printer, 1614 Apr 4] (Box 1)
      Autograph MS, signed "Vera copia,
      Henry Elsynge, Richard Rosseter".
      Endorsed "copie of Mr Barker his bill
      delivered unto mee 28 Oct 1614."
      f.40.
  - BARKER, ROBERT, D.1645
    - [List of books and paper delivered to Sir Thomas Smith, Clerk of the House of Lords, 1603/4 Feb 10] (Box 1)
      Autograph MS, page torn. Includes
      statute books, Book of Common Prayer,
      and a Bible, with prices.
      f.41.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1621. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Barons to whom writs of summons to appear at the Parliament have been delivered, 1620/1 Jan 20] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS.
      Endorsed by Robert Bowyer: "Receaved
      from Mr Camell of ye Pettibagge."
      f.42.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1641.
    - "The Remonstrance of both houses of Parliament unto the King delivered by the Lord Keeper ...", [1640/1] (Box 1)
      [1640/1 Jan 29]
      Contemporary MS copy.
      Against the priests and Jesuits.
      Rushworth, v.4, 158.
      f.43.
  - JOHN BROWNE, D.1691
    - [List of bills to be re-enacted by Parliament, c.1661], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Autograph MS.
      List includes Triennial bill, the
      bills for abolishing Star Chamber
      and Ship Money, etc.
      f.44.
  - CHARLES II, KING OF GREAT BRITAIN, 1630-1685
    - [Order to the Dean of Westminster to remove certain persons buried in Henry VII's chapel, 1661 Sept 9], n.d. (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy, endorsed by
      John Browne. Includes John Pym,
      Elizabeth Cromwell, and some
      regicides.
      f.46.
  - JOHN BROWNE, D.1691
    - [The account made by the feoffees for the inns and lands in Chipping Warden for charitable uses, 1666 Aug 17] (Box 1)
      Autograph MS. Account of income and
      expenditures.
      f.47.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1628. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - "An abstract of the Parliament", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      6 p.
      Anonymous MS. [1628]
      Notes of the proceedings in the House
      of Lords divided into headings such
      as 'general orders' and 'Private
      business'.
      f.48.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1661. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [The evidence in the case between Sir Henry Frederick Thynne and Sir James Thynne, 1661 Dec 16 & 1661/2 Jan 9] (Box 1)
      MS in the hand of John Browne.
      Evidence on a bill in the Lords
      concerning land disputes among the
      Thynne family. LJ, xi, 351 & 361.
      f.49.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1629. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [List of the spiritual and temporal peers in Parliament, 1628/9 Jan 20] (Box 1)
      MS. LJ, iv, 5.
      f.50.
  - [TRESHAM, FRANCIS, 1567-1605]
    - [The letter written to Lord Monteagle warning him to stay away from Parliament, 1605 Oct 26], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy. Anonymous
      letter to William Parker, baron
      Monteagle (1575-1622) which exposed
      the Gunpowder Plot. This letter is
      usually attributed to Tresham.
      f.51.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1660.
    - [List of acts of Parliament, 1660], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      f.52.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1670.
    - [A brief of the bill for making navigable the rivers Brandon and Wayney, 1669/70 Mar 21] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy. The bill was
      read in the House of Lords 1669/70
      Mar 22. LJ, xii, 319.
      f.53.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1661.
    - [Declaration to the King concerning his marriage, 1661 May 13], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy, partly in the
      hand of John Browne. LJ, xi, 252.
      f.54.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1662. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [The proviso to the Militia Bill, 1662, May 13], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy. Concerns
      assessment of peers for horses and
      arms. LJ, xi, 458.
      f.55.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1662. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - "The Lords Proviso in the Bill for the Militia, 16 May 1662", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy. On military
      responsibilities & contributions of
      peers. LJ, xi, 464.
      f.56.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1662. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Statement by the House of Lords concerning their privileges in the case of money bills, 1662 May 19], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Draft copy. LJ, xi, 469.
      f.57.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1661. HOUSE OF COMMONS.
    - [Message to the House of Lords desiring their concurrence in moving the King to declare a Fast Day, 1661 May 31], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy. Mentioned in
      CJ, viii, 262 and LJ, xi, 269.
      f.58.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1661. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - "The Lords' Protestation in passing the bill for paving the streets about West[minster], 1661 July 30", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy in the hand of
      John Browne. LJ, xi, 328 and f.62 in
      this index.
      f.59.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1661.
    - [List of bills passed by both Houses and assented to by the King, 1661 Dec 20] (Box 1)
      MS copy in the hand of John Browne.
      Nine bills listed.
      f.60.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1662. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Report of the Lord Chief Justice of the Common Pleas on the dispute between Yarmouth and Lowestoft over fishing rights, 1661/2 Feb 22] (Box 1)
      Draft copy. LJ, xi, 392.
      f.61.
  - JOHN BROWNE, D.1691
    - [Extracts from the Journals of the House of Lords on the rights of the Lords in regards to money bills, 1578/8 Mar 22 & 1661 July 30], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      LJ, ii, 141 and xi, 328.
      f.62.
  - JOHN BROWNE, D.1691
    - [Extracts from the Journals of Parliament concerning the precedents of addresses to the King by both Houses and by each House separately, 1662-1666] (Box 1)
      f.63.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1664. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Order in Parliament to the Surveyor General directing him to open the sewer near the Tower in order to protect the records of Parliament. 1664 May 5], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy. LJ, xi, 608.
      f.64.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1666. HOUSE OF COMMONS.
    - [Message to the House of Lords concerning the appointment of commissioners to examine the public accounts, 1666 Nov 9], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy. LJ, xii, 36.
      f.65.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1666. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Order by the House of Lords that Lord Butler must apologize to the House and to Lord Ashley for some harsh words, 1666 Nov 19] (Box 1)
      Draft copy. LJ, xii, 31.
      f.66.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1666. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Order freeing Dr George Wake from restraint, 1666 Nov 28], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Autograph MS signed by Jo.Browne.
      Wake was in custody for issuing out
      a process against Lord Rockingham.
      LJ, xii, 36.
      f.67.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1668. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Order that shortness of time is never to be used as an argument for passing bills without due consideration, 1668 May 5], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy, corrected.
      LJ, xii, 242.
      f.68.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1668. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Order appointing a committee to move the King to defer the adjournment of Parliament so that a dispute between the two Houses may be settled, 1668 May 5], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy. LJ, xii, 242.
      f.69.
  - CHARLES II, KING OF GREAT BRITAIN, 1630-1685
    - [Report of the King's speech to Parliament in the House of Lords, 1669/70 Feb 22 and an order in the House of Lords, 1669/70 Feb 23] (Box 1)
      John Browne. Concerns Skinner's case.
      Cobbett, v.4, 444.
      f.70.
  - [BECKMAN FAMILY]
    - [A brief of a bill before Parliament concerning the lands of John Beckman, 1669/70 Mar 1] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy. Bill to enable
      family to sell lands to pay debts.
      LJ, xii, 296.
      f.72.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1670.
    - [A brief of a bill in Parliament for the Deeping Fens, 1668/70 Mar 18], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy. LJ, xii, 313
      (First reading of the bill).
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1660.
    - [Statement on the government of the Church of England, c.1660] (Box 1)
      Contemporary draft copy. Parliament
      will consider all things necessary to
      the settling and peace of the Church.
      f.73.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1645.
    - [Letter to Scotland giving the names of Parliament's new commissioners to Scotland, 1644 July] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy. The
      commissioners are the Earl of
      Rutland, Sir William Armire, Sir
      Henry Vane the Younger, and others.
      CJ, iv, 206.
      f.74.
  - CHARLES II, KING OF GREAT BRITAIN, 1630-1685
    - [A report of the King's speech in the House of Lords delivered by the Lord Chancellor, 1672/3 Mar 8], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Draft copy in the hand of John
      Browne. A report of the King's
      decision to cancel the Declaration
      for the suspension of the Penal Laws.
      LJ, xii, 549.
      f.75.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1644.
    - "The Parliaments answer to the States General Propositions", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      [c.1644]
      Contemporary MS copy. Answer to the
      offer of the States-General to
      mediate a peace between Parliament
      and the King, and a decision on the
      restitution of ships.
      f.76.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691
    - [List of ships, c.1660's], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      f.77.
  - MONTROSE, JAMES GRAHAM, 1ST MARQUIS OF, 1612-1650
    - [Instructions given by the Earl of Montrose, 1641 May], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Also includes "Instructions from Lord
      Traquair." Notes on a Scottish
      conspiracy in favor of King Charles
      I. Published in 1641. John Stewart,
      1st earl of Traquair (d.1659).
      f.78.
  - WHITEHEAD, WILLIAM
    - "The most sad case of William Whitehead one of his Maties Messengers", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      [late 1660]
      Draft copy with corrections. Account
      of the losses he suffered under the
      Parliamentary party and his attempt
      to gain a place in the King's
      service.
      f.79.
  - CHARLES I, KING OF GREAT BRITAIN, 1660-1649
    - "The King's speech at dissolving the Parliament", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      [1640 May 5]
      3 p.
      John Browne. Rushworth, v.3, 1154.
      f.80.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, C.1669. HOUSE OF COMMONS.
    - [Speech by a member of the House upon presenting the King with two subsidy bills], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS. The titles of the
      two bills have been left out. The
      subsidies were granted in
      consideration of "ye extraordinary
      charge that for four years last past
      have attended the maintenance of the
      government and likewise yr Matys
      great debt."
      f.81.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691
    - [Accounts for the levying of coat and conduct money in Middlesex, 1640 July 22] (Box 1)
      Autograph MS. Includes list of names
      and amounts due, as well as excuses
      for not paying. (Another document on
      C & C money in "Parl. 1599-1641,"
      p.179).
      f.82.
  - ELSYNG, HENRY, 1577-1636?
    - [Notes on King James I's speech to Parliament, 1614 Apr 5], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Autograph MS. Includes a note by
      Robert Bowyer (d.1621) that his
      "nephew Elsyng" sat in the House of
      Lords and took notes for him this
      day.
      f.83-84.
  - ELSYNG, HENRY, 1577-1636?
    - [Notes on Parliament, 16th century], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Autograph MS in English and Latin.
      Notes on legislation and statutes.
      f.85.
  - BOWYER, ROBERT, D.1621
    - "A Note of Fees paid to the Clerk of the Upper house in 1621", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy, edges frayed.
      Endorsed: "This coppie was writt out
      of a noat that Mr Bowyer had writt
      with his own hand." Fees includes
      those due from the Lords and charges
      for copying bills. Notes added in
      1623.
      f.86.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [Letter from a Steward to his Lord, 17th century], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Anonymous MS. On land rentals and
      estate business.
      f.87.
  - FOXE, THOMAS
    - "To the right honourable the Earle of Rutland, the humble petition of Thomas Foxe his honours Tenant and servant" (Box 1)
      [17th century]
      MS.
      Defends himself against accusations
      of dishonesty and misdeeds.
      f.88.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1641. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Extracts from the Journals of the House concerning the court of York, 1641 Apr 27, May 29, June 10], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      f.89.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1610.
    - "Necessaries for the parliament howse, January 1609", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      [1609/10]
      Anonymous MS. List of statute books,
      BCP, almanacs, etc.
      f.90.
  - [BOWYER, ROBERT, D.1621]
    - "Fees receaved by RB for certificates", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      [1619]
      Received by the Clerk of Parliament
      for certifying private acts.
      f.91.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691
    - [Receipt for 750L due to Browne and Richard Branthwaite, 1642 Jan 20] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy. Due from Sir
      William Spencer, bart. (1608-1647),
      paid by Sir Robert Pye (1585-1662).
      f.92.
  - SPENCER, SIR WILLIAM, BART., 1608-1647
    - [Warrant to Sir Robert Pye to pay 70L to Richard Rowley and a receipt for 70L, 1640 Nov] (Box 1)
      MS. John Browne and Nathaniell Harris
      sign as witnesses. Receipt signed by
      Samuel Rowley.
      f.93.
  - [OLDISWORTH, MICHAEL]
    - "The Earl of Pembrokes speech in the House of Peers when the seven Lords were accused of High Treason", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy, half page
      missing. A satire on the Earl of
      Pembroke. Reprinted in 1693 (see
      Beinecke Broadsides 4, box 6, 1693).
      f.96.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1685. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Order in the House of Lords concerning the petition of Alexander Smith and others, 1685 June 1] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy. Concerning a
      land dispute. LJ, xiv, 24 & 36.
      f.97.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1685. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Order concerning the petition of Sir Oliver Butler, 1685 June 1], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Writ of Errors that Butler has
      pending in the House. LJ, xiv, 24.
      f.98.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1641. HOUSE OF COMMONS.
    - "Resolutions concerning the Court of the President and Council in the North" (Box 1)
      [1641 Apr 24]
      Contemporary MS copy. Resolutions
      against the Court. CJ, ii, 127.
      f.99.
  - NORTHAMPTONSHIRE. ENGLISH CITIZENS.
    - [Petition to Parliament, c.1650], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy. Petition for a
      fairer representation in Parliament
      and on religion and the army.
      f.100.
  - CHARLES I, KING OF GREAT BRITAIN, 1660-1649
    - [The King's speech to Parliament upon his return from Scotland, 1641 Dec 2] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy. LJ, iv, 459.
      f.101.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1645. COMMITTEE OF THE WEST.
    - [Resolution reported in the House of Lords, 1645 Sep 3], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy. Resolution
      that Sir Thomas Fairfax ought not to
      accept soldiers into his army who
      have left the forces of Colonel
      Massey for lack of pay. LJ, vii, 565.
      f.102.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1643. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Order for a conference with the House of Commons concerning the Queen's safety and passage, c.1642/3 Feb] (Box 1)
      Browne. The Lords condemn the firing
      upon Henrietta Maria queen consort of
      Charles I in Yorkshire and offer her
      safe conduct to join her husband.
      f.103.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1646. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [A copy of a letter communicated to the House of Commons to be sent to the States of Scotland, 1646 June 15] (Box 1)
      Contemporary draft copy. Letter of
      thanks to Scottish lords for their
      continued efforts to bring about
      peace.
      f.104.
  - CHARLES II, KING OF GREAT BRITAIN, 1630-1685
    - [The King's speech to Parliament, 1675 Oct 13], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy. Asks for
      supplies and admits to some
      extravagance.
      CJ, ix, 357.
      f.105.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691
    - [Extracts and notes from the writings of the Bishop of Hereford and "Doderidge", 1683 Aug 28] (Box 1)
      On Parliament and political events,
      probably from the works of Francis
      Godwin, bp of Hereford (1567-1633)
      and Sir Philip Doddridge of John
      Doddridge.
      f.106.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691
    - [Letter to Mr Budd, 1681 Aug 29], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Autograph MS, torn. Angry letter to
      Budd showing that he, with his
      master, has been spreading lies
      about Browne.
      f.107.
  - HURLEY, MARY
    - [Receipts and accounts of money lent to Mrs Pinley, 1733-1738] (Box 1)
      MS, two items are torn.
      f.108.
  - LADD, SAMUEL
    - [Letter to James Cotes, 1669 Oct 11], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      ALS. On agricultural business.
      f.109.
  - FLETCHER, HENRY
    - [Memorandum on sums owed by Thomas Deans and William Hanway, collectors of the assessment in the city of Gloucester in 1651, 1661 Oct 14] (Box 1)
      MS endorsed: "Mr Henry Fletchers
      Notes..."
      f.110.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691
    - [Marriage settlement between Elizabeth, daughter of John Browne, and Toby Chancey, 1665/6 Jan 12] (Box 1)
      Draft copy with corrections.
      Agreement on Elizabeth Browne's
      portion and provisions for heirs.
      f.111.
  - NO CATALOGUE INFO FOR 112-115
    - (all documents in Spanish with embossed Gonzaga seal) (Box 1)